# GABRIEL'S CURRICULUM VITAE

## PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : GABRIEL LEE KIN HENG

Gender : Male
Health : Excellent
Marital Status : Single
Race : Chinese
Religion : Buddhism

Nationality : Malaysian (Singapore PR)



## **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To use my knowledge and skills applied towards achieving the corporate goals and to be a valuable asset to the organization. To secure a challenging position in a reputable organization to expand my knowledge about new and emerging trends in the IT sector.

## **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

I have about 7 years' work experience in IT sector. Currently I am Application Consultant at CPF Board. I currently involved in the Healthcare project, my main responsibilities are conducting requirement gathering, reviewing and analyzing the system design and also doing the development using JAVA, NodeJS and related web programming.

I used to be a System Analyst at StarHub Ltd, my main responsibilities were maintaining StarHub's Enterprise Web Application and ChatBot system, conducting requirement gathering, analyzing existing system and user's requirement, project schedule planning, system design, system implementation and UAT testing when there is any new requirement or enhancement project.

I used to be a Web Application Developer at NCS Pte Ltd but most of the time I was allocated at IRAS to handled and developed the new project initialed by IRAS. The primary technical skills

required for IRAS project are HTML, JavaScript, CSS, C#, ASP.Net, SQL Server, DB2 database etc.

I have successfully completed more than 5 times complete SDLC (included planning, analysis, design, development, implementation and testing) and obtained Agile Scrum Master cert (PSM 1) in 2016.

## **EXPERIENCE**

June 2019 – Current

#### **Central Provident Fund Board**

## **Application Consultant**

- Manage outsourced vendors to implement and maintain IT applications in cloud environment
- Analyse requirements and perform high level feasibility study for IT solution
- Review impact analysis, design of IT solution and cost estimation proposed by outsourced vendor
- Perform quality checks on IT solution
- Monitor and provide updates for project development phases and deliverables
- Design and develop the software testing automation script using Tricentic Tosca
- Provide support to users of the IT application systems
- Work with Cloud service provider, application vendors and other agency to ensure systems delivered are resilient and secured

## **Reason of leaving:**

• Looking for permanent role and better professional growth

## Nov 2016 – May 2019

#### StarHub Ltd

## **System Analysts**

- Manage customer-facing application for enterprise business and consumer markets.
- Defined enterprise self-care application roadmap based on operational needs, sales requirement, customers' feedback and market trends.
- Analyze consumer and business trends based on statistics obtained from numerous operational systems and feedback channels.
- Identify automation opportunities in existing processes to streamline operations, increase productivity and enhance customer experience.
- Drive successful product adoption.
- Coordinate product development of enterprise self-care system.
- Vendor engagement for development and testing.
- Design system and define the workflow according to internal and external users' need.

# **Projects involved:**

- 1. StarHub's My Business Account (Page <u>URL</u>) This is a customer self-help portal that helping business/corporate customer to manage their account related service. In this project, my role is to defines the application problem by conferring with internal and external users. Designing the application UI, improving and analyzing the system work flow and processes. Provide reference by writing documentation and validates the result by testing the programs.
- 2. StarHub's ChatBot (Link to the application) This is a virtual assistant that simulates human conversation or chat via artificial intelligence (A.I.). The ChatBot is able to handle customer's enquiry such as Billing, Account information, Promotion, Mobile and Broadband service enquiry. My role in this project is to define the business uses case, design the system workflow, conducting the data training for machine learning and artificial intelligence, system integration and system testing. Besides, I have to engage with StarHub's customer service agent to understanding their needs and the problem they are facing so that we are able to improve the ChatBot ability.

## **Reason of leaving:**

- I would like to look for more responsibility and grow in career, wish to get more emerge knowledge relevant to technology.
- Due to job scope changed after re-organization.

#### **NCS Pte Ltd**

## **Application Consultant**

Projects involved:

- 1. **HRConnects (Web Application) for Ministry of Foreign Affairs Singapore** My primary role in this project is to handle and develop the contract renewal and Employee re-deployment module.
  - **Skills Used:** C#.net, ASP.net, SSRS Report tool, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, Entity Framework, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS.
- 2. **IRAS AIS Online for Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore** To implement and develop a system that to help IRAS retrieve the employee data from CPF. Besides, I have to design and develop the IRAS E-Service web page that it is AIS Employment Income deployed on 29 December 2014
  - **Skills Used:** C#.net, DB2 database, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, NUnit, AQT, Microsoft Visio, IBM DataStage (ETL tools), IBM Cognos Report Tool, Entity Framework, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS.
- 3. **IRAS MyInfo for Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore** Second Project for IRAS Singapore. This project is to implement web service that to help IRAS to retrieve the Taxpayer data from IDA MyInfo portal. This is the first project in IRAS to implement a web service to retrieve Taxpayer information from others government agency. Besides that, I have to setup and deploy the IBM DataPower SOA Appliance, it is to control and manage the web service traffic between IRAS and others government agency. The target deployment of this project is Jan 2016.
  - Skills Used: C#.net, DB2 database, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, Entity Framework, NUnit, AQT, Microsoft Visio, IBM DataStage (ETL tools), IBM Cognos Report Tool, IBM DataPower (SOA Appliance), SOAP Web Service, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS/CSS3, Bootstrap, PowerShell Script.
- 4. **IRAS Electronic Data Exchange Gateway (EDX)** Application maintenance and support for Electronic Data Exchange (EDX) gateway system for EASY authentication for subscribing agencies.
  - **Skills Used**: Java, JSP, iPlanet, Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and Transport Layer Security (TLS), Microsoft SQL Server, SOAP Web Service, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS.

- 5. **IRAS Case Management System (CMS)** To develop a new Case Management System, an investigative workbench for management and tracking of Taxpayer's Case records. Responsible for development of IRIN integration function in .Net and IBM DataStage (ETL tools) with Case Management System.
  - **Skills Used**: C#.Net, IBM DataStage (ETL tools), NUnit, DB2 database, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, Entity Framework, NUnit, AQT.
- 6. **IRAS myTax Portal Web Revamps Release 3** Revamps existing IRAS' eService website (myTax Portal) to Responsive Web Design. My primary role in this project is to analyzing the system work flow, and developing the system GUI based on users' requirement.
  - **Skills Used**: C#.net, HTML, CSS3, JavaScript and JQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Ajax, DB2 database, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, Entity Framework, AQT.

## **Reason of leaving:**

• Limited career growth and advancement

#### Mar 2013 - Feb 2014

#### Blue Ocean Data Solution SDN. BHN.

# **Software Engineer**

- Analysis and provide pointers to those needing problem resolutions.
- Perform system design, implementation, enhancement, maintenance and support.
- Designing coding and debugging application in various software languages according SDLC.
- To evaluate the existing system or application to identify areas for improvements.
- To handle software release, installation and upgrading process.
- Develop and update operation procedure and associated SDLC documentations.
- Provide on-site technical support and system trouble shooting.
- Responsible for additional tasks as assigned by management from time to time.
- Maintaining and managing Database system.
- Responsible for meeting customer for software application, if required.
- Software Development
  - Previous project:

- Laundry Management System (C#, Crystal Report, MS SQL Server, MS Access, Cloud and Radio-Frequency Identification (RFID))
- Dormitory Management System (VB.net, Crystal Report, MS Office Excel Reporting, MS SQL Server)
- Attendances Management System (JAVA, MS Access, MS Office Excel Reporting)

# **Reason of leaving:**

- Looking for new challenge
- Looking for a more stable working environment
- Transport Problem, because company relocation

## **EDUCATION**

## 2017 - 2019

- Bachelor of Science (Honours) Software Engineering from University of Portsmouth
- First Class Honours
- CGPA 4.07

# 2013

- Diploma in Information Technology in Olympia College Johor Bahru
- CGPA 3.45

## 2009

- Secondary Education (Sekolah Menengah Kebangsaan Taman Molek)
- Highest Qualification: Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM)

## ACHIEVEMENTS & EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Certificate of achievement (LCCI Level 2 in Book-keeping and Accounts) (2009)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in Programming in C++)
   (2011)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in Visual Basic Programming)
   (2012)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in Java Programming)
   (2013)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in Data Communication and Networking)
   (2012)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in IT And Society)
   (2012)
- Agile Project Scrum Master (**PSM1**) (2016)
- University of Portsmouth Top Student Awards (2019)

# **SKILLS AND ABILITIES**

# Languages

• Proficiency in English - Speaking -7, Written- 5

Proficiency in Malay
 Speaking- 6, Written- 3

• Proficiency in Chinese - Speaking- 10, Written- 9

• Proficiency in Dialect

(Hokkien, Cantonese) - Speaking- 7

# **SKILLSET**

Skillsets	No. Years Of Experience	Level	
Programming Language			
ASP.Net	5	Advanced	
C#	5	Advanced	
SQL Statement	5	Advanced	
Node.JS	2	Intermediate	
JAVA	4	Intermediate	
VB.Net	3	Intermediate	
VB6	2	Intermediate	
Golang	1	Intermediate	
PowerShell	1	Intermediate	
Python	1	Beginner	
C/C++	1	Beginner	
Web Programming Language			
HTML	5	Advanced	
CSS	5	Advanced	
JavaScript	5	Advanced	
JQuery	5	Advanced	
XML	4	Advanced	
XSLT	1	Beginner	

Web Framework			
.Net Framework 4 & above	5	Advanced	
Bootstrap	5	Advanced	
Angular 7	3	Intermediate	
AngularJS	1	Beginner	
WCF Service	4	Advanced	
SOAP Web Service	4	Advanced	
RESTFul Web Service	4	Advanced	
Application / Software			
Visual Studio	5	Advanced	
Team Foundation Server (TFS Source	4	Advanced	
Control System)			
NUnit	4	Intermediate	
DialogFlow (Google On Action)	3	Intermediate	
Advanced Query Tools (AQT)	3	Advanced	
Microsoft SQL Server Management	4	Advanced	
2008			
NetBean	2	Intermediate	
IBM InfoSphere DataStage (ETL	3	Advanced	
Tools)			
IBM Cognos Report	3	Advanced	
Crystal Report	2	Intermediate	
Microsoft Office Package	5	Advanced	
Microsoft Visio	4	Advanced	
SoupUI	3	Intermediate	
Appliance			
IBM DataPower Gateway (SOA	2	Intermediate	
Appliances)			
Radio Frequency Identification	3	Intermediate	
(RDIF)			

## OTHER RELEVANT SKILLS

- Have Full SDLC experience
- Agile Scrum Master (PSM1)
- Knows maintenance on computer's hardware and software.
- Have basic accounting knowledge (LCCI Level 2).
- Patient and eager to learn new technology such AI, Data Mining, Big Data and Data Analyst.

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

**Availability** : 1 month notice

## REFERENCE

#### Reference 1

Name : Tok Woon Boon

**Telephone No.** : +65 94594585

**Email** : woonboon.tok@gmail.com

**Position** : Senior Manager

**Company** : Oversea-Chinese Banking Corporation Limited

## Reference 2

Name : Joey Lai Poh Chi
Telephone No. : +65 96264784

Email : Joey\_LAI\_Poh\_Chi@iras.gov.sg

**Position** : Account Manager

**Company** : Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore